Guide to the Papers of the Cavendish-Talbot Family Folger MS X.d.428 (1-203)
Folger Shakespeare Library
- Cavendish-Talbot family papers, 1548-1607; Series 1; X.d.428 (1-147)
  - Correspondence, 1.1
    - Letter from George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, Sheffield, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, ca. 1575?; X.d.428 (99)
      Refers to conflicts in their respective building projects. Does not like the way she hinders him and his works by keeping so many men. Asks her to take order for the plate, damask, diaper napkins and sheets, for there are no damask or diaper napkins in the house (Sheffield).
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/wn85j8
    - Letter from George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, Sheffield, to Avery Copley, 1579 April 6; X.d.428 (100)
      Asks him to make a survey of the town fields in the township of Elland, Yorkshire preparatory to a partition.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/m062w6
    - Letter from George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, Sheffield, to Avery Copley, Batley, Yorkshire, 1579/80 February 28; X.d.428 (101)
      On behalf of his cousin Edward Savile, Copley is to survey the town fields of Elland.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/hq629g
    - Letter from George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, Sheffield, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1580 June 21; X.d.428 (102)
      Her Majesty seems unlikely to allow "her" (Mary, Queen of Scots?), to go to Buxton. Will send some wine from Wingfield to Buxton.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/ctlpi4
    - Letter from George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, Sheffield, to Gilbert Talbot, 1580 September 12; X.d.428 (103)
      To be delivered to his wife, Elizabeth, Countess of Shrewsbury. He has intercepted Bagshawe's letter. This and others have caused him great amusement.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/107o37
    - Letter from George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1580 October 10; X.d.428 (104)
      He cannot write in his own hand because it is "so trobled with paine and stifnes." Returns the Earl of Leicester's letter, and asks his wife when she writes again to Leicester to say he (Shrewsbury) has no doubt of his remembering the grant of payment.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/03i9l6
    - Letter from George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, to Avery Copley and Hugh Byston, 1584 June 7; X.d.428 (105)
      Spare not his purse and the regard of his honor and learn how long the Earl of Leicester will be there.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/l9gxxe
    - Letter from George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, Orton Longueville, Huntingdonshire, to Avery Copley, 1586/7 January 1; X.d.428 (106)
      Particulars as to how he is to dispose of Mr. Savile's rent.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/lb7rsc
    - Letter from Gilbert Talbot to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1574 June 28; X.d.428 (107)
      Written from the court at Greenwich. The queen "styrreth litell abrode." Much talk about "this Late proclamation for apparell which is thought shall be very severely executed" (STC 8066). Has written to his father concerning the brute at court of his being sick again, which he believes is "vtterly vntrew." Lady Cobham asks daily after her, and sends her commendations.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/03p06w
    - Letter from Gilbert Talbot, Shrewsbury Place, London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1575 May 14; X.d.428 (108)
      All are well at Hackney (the Lennox's). Discusses "thos leude fellowes of the peake" and their suit. His sister Pembroke is strong again, and the Queen sends to her continually.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/2a28qs
    - Letter from Gilbert Talbot, Wingfield, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1576 May 28; X.d.428 (109)
      Nothing worthy advertising. The Earl is at Wingfield, but returns to Sheffield tomorrow.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/410ph5
    - Letter from Gilbert Talbot, Buxton, Derbyshire, to George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, and Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1578 June 30?; X.d.428 (110)
      He delivered their packet to Leicester this morning. News of Leicester's plans on leaving Buxton for Chatsworth. Mentions the foul weather. Suggests he should defer Lady Lennox's suits to the Queen until he returns to the court.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/nl87by
    - Letter from Gilbert Talbot to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1577 July?; X.d.428 (111)
      His father wanted to know what Gilbert had discussed with his mother, which Gilbert recounted to the Earl in great detail (concerning the bitterness between his parents, and a dispute over his mother's embroiderers). P.S. The letters from Sir John Constable were to warn her about two Scots that were travelling with linen cloth to sell, that had letters of importance to this Queen. Mentions also a letter from Lord Huntington.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/t6i4it
    - Letter from Gilbert Talbot and Mary Talbot Sheffield, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1577 August 1; X.d.428 (112)
      News of her husband's movements. Recounts further conversations between him and his father concerning their parents' marital discord. P.S. their son George drinks to his grandmother, "Lady Danmode," every day.
      Signed also by Mary.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/gouvv2
    - Letter from Gilbert Talbot and Mary Talbot to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1583? September 19; X.d.428 (113)
      Recounts the points of discussion between himself, his father, and the Earl of Rutland. Mentions a swelling in his father's body and other news. Asks if the Queen will be offended if he goes to Newark to the Earl.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/m0xd33
    - Letter from Gilbert Talbot and Mary Talbot to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1589? February; X.d.428 (114)
      News they have gleaned on the Queen's highway while traveling to Dunstable, mostly concerning parliament. P.S. in Mary's hand, written from Beskewod where they left Mrs. Markham, wishing a happy long life to the Countess, Lady Arbella and others.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/5119zu
    - Letter from Gilbert Talbot and Mary Talbot to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1589 July 1; X.d.428 (115)
      Still delayed with daily promises in trying to dispatch their business. The Earl of Essex was going to renew his suit to the queen for Tutbury, but is willing to "surcease" his suit to further Gilbert therein. Description of the wicked murder of the French king, by a friar, it is thought. P.S. in Mary's hand: Nothing has been performed "for your ladyship's case;" concerning Welbeck, "it is much mor bacward then it semed;" the Queen has asked very carefully after Lady Arbella.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/l6ikk8
    - Letter from Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, Whitehall Palace, to Mr. John Harpur, Esq., Swarkeston, Derbyshire, 1603 March 30; X.d.428 (116)
      Informs his good friends in Derbyshire and Staffordshire that he (Shrewsbury) may be entertaining the King at Worksop, Nottinghamshire, and asks for their company. He will not refuse any fat capons, hens, partridges or the like if the King come to him.
      This is a copy in the hand of John Curzon, who adds a P.S. stating that he had received the letter from his cousin Harpur so that his friends may consider it.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/m22xu1
    - Letter from Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, the court at Theobalds, to Thomas Smethwicke, 1604 July 27; X.d.428 (117)
      Informs him that Lord Berwick has bought the fee farm of the manor of Hartington, Derbyshire. Chastises him in a P.S.
      True copy. Also, a true copy of a letter to his brother-in-law Henry Cavendish, of the same date and pertaining to the same matter.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/p524qc
    - Letter from Mary Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Dowager Countess of Shrewsbury, 1607? July 8; X.d.428 (118)
      Thanks her for the well wrought ermine (armen), which shall lie by her daughter of Arundel the day of the christening (of Lady Arundel's son James) but no longer. She is glad to hear that the countess's hip pain has declined. The Queen removed to Theobalds yesterday. The King, Queen, and Lord Chamberlain will attend the christening.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/kb260l
    - Letter from Mary Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, Sheffield Lodge, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Dowager Countess of Shrewsbury, 1607? December 30; X.d.428 (119)
      Sends New Year's greetings with the present of a cushion for her to use every day at prayer, which is in the same pattern as the bed of Mary's daughter, the Countess of Arundel.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/ooun2f
    - Letter from Lady Dorothy Stafford, Westminster, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Dowager Countess of Shrewsbury, 1600/1601 January 13; X.d.428 (120)
      Has presented her and Lady Arbella's New Year's gifts to the Queen, who has taken a special liking to the Countess's gift. The Queen told Lady Stafford that she would be careful of Lady Arbella, to whom the Queen has sent a token "which is not so good as I Could wish it," compared to what Lady Arbella gave the queen. Asks her not to share the news of the Queen's expressing her care of Arbella with others.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/bp43a8
    - Letter from Anne Talbot, Baynard's Castle, London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1575? May 8; X.d.428 (121)
      Her sister of Pembroke has been extremely ill, but is now recovering and sends her greetings. A progress is imminent.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/3n56p9
    - Letter from Anne Talbot, Earith, Huntingdonshire, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1575? May 29; X.d.428 (122)
      She comes to the court so seldom that she can give her stepmother-in-law little news. Fears her sister Pembroke's delivery will not fall out so well.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/77sw09
    - Letter from Francis Talbot, from court, to George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, 1573? May 23; X.d.428 (123)
      Informs his father of French and Scottish news. The castle at Edinburgh likely to be taken very shortly. There is some talk of a progress to Bristol. Mr. Christopher? Hatton wants to go to the spa because of his great sickness.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/t393qr
    - Letter from Francis Talbot, the court at Greenwich, to George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, 1574 May 10; X.d.428 (124)
      Has learnt nothing of Corker (an ex-chaplain of the Earl of Shrewsbury's), who is still prisoner in the Fleet; the matter is almost forgotten. The Queen means to go to Bristol on her progress. King Phillip is going to Flanders, and the Queen's navy is preparing to go to sea.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/5dtte4
    - Letter from Richard Topcliffe, Rycote, Oxfordshire, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1577 July 9; X.d.428 (125)
      The Earl of Leicester has departed toward the court to Sir Thomas Gresham's after being at Buxton, Derbyshire, to treat his boil. Has never heard Leicester commend Buxton half so much. The Countess of Bedford, the Earl and Countess of Cumberland, and Lord Wharton and his wife have arrived at Rycote, and "the fatte Erle cummethe this day." Leicester is very careful over his two young cousins, Edward and Henry, to have them placed at Oxford and will bring his "owld deade sewt vnto a newe lyffe" on behalf of her son Charles.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/46yiv4
    - Letter from Sir Francis Willoughby, Buxton, Derbyshire, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1589 April 26; X.d.428 (126)
      Asks her to lend her horse litter and furniture to his wife, who, failing to recover her health at Buxton, has decided to come home.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/7q7nn2
    - Letter from Anthony Wingfield, the court at Windsor, to Elizabeth Wingfield, 1575 October 13; X.d.428 (127)
      Anthony Wingfield (1506-1593) was a Gentleman Usher and Gentleman of the Black Rod. Married first to Margaret Blennerhasset, then ca. 1559 to Jane Purpett and then ca. 1562 to Elizabeth Leake.
      Elizabeth Wingfield (b. ca. 1530) was a Gentlewoman of the Privy Chamber and Mother of the Maids. She was the daughter of Ralph and Elizabeth Leake and the half sister of Elziabeth Hardwick.
      Informs his wife of the different suggestions of the Countess of Sussex and Lady Cobham as to a suitable gift for the Queen. A safeguard and a cloak described in detail.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/f0a0sd
    - Letter from Anthony Wingfield, the court, to Elizabeth Wingfield, ca. 1575 December 13; X.d.428 (128)
      Recounts further opinions of the Countess of Sussex on the New Year's gift. Recommends certain colours and embroidery designs. The Queen likes the pansy flower best.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/1510g3
    - Letter from Elizabeth Wingfield, St. John's (SenIons), London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1568? October 21; X.d.428 (129)
      Mr. Wingfield delivered the venison to the Queen and she talked one long hour of the Earl and Countess, saying of the Countess, "I haue bene glade to se my lady Sayntloa but now more dyssirous to se my lady Shrewsbury ... there ys no lady ys thys land that I beter loue and lyke." On overleaf, a list of women and men in the Countess of Shrewsbury's hand, headed by the Queen, ending with "countery wemen," and including various noblemen and women.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/e9vrs0
    - Letter from Elizabeth Wingfield to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1576 or 1577? January 2; X.d.428 (130)
      The Queen told the Earl of Leicester and the Lord Chamberlain "that she neuer had any [garments] so well lyked her" as the Countess's New Year's gift, and especially liked "the color and strange triminge." All are well at Hackney (the Lennox's), and Lady Arbella is a good child. Asks after Lord George (her grandson, the son of Gilbert and Mary, who died in 1577, age 2.)
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/8mlv18
    - Letter from Elizabeth Wingfield, St. John's (S. Iones), London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, ca. 1585? December 8; X.d.428 (131)
      Lady Cobham does not advise a gift in money. Lady Arbella is "so good a childe as can be." The tailor only has five and a quarter yards of green velvet for a gown for Lady Arbella, but they need seven yards. The Queen "gaue many good wordes what she woulde do for yow h[onour]," concerning "my lords harde dealinge."
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/x8h8t3
    - Letter from unidentified lady to Lady Mary Sidney, ca. 1585?; X.d.428 (132)
      Thanks her for her good opinion. Asks her to "dispose wholly of me as you wills doe of your owne sister, or what frend ells you make very deare reckninge of." Humbly thanks the Queen for her remembrance of the writer.
      Unsigned, with numerous corrections, but sealed and addressed.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/u6e5w5
  - Other documents, 1.2
    - Account of household expenses, 1559 September; X.d.428 (133)
      A list of payments for staff and others, including £4 delivered to Master Clement St. Loe from "my mastur my lady" (presumably, Sir William St. Loe and Elizabeth, later Countess of Shrewsbury), and £21 10 shillings for 2 chains of gold, which "my lady dyd geve to my masturs systur."
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/1op7n6
    - Account of household expenses, ca. 1565; X.d.428 (134)
      List of items to be purchased to make nightgowns and coats for the children (all but Henry) of George, Earl of Shrewbury.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/2n8h4f
    - Account of household expenses, undated; X.d.428 (135)
      Mostly clothing material items. Includes two purses for the bride and bride's groom.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/2i9x1s
    - Copy of petition from the tenants adjoining the royal forest of the Peak, Derbyshire, to Elizabeth I, Queen of England, August 13, 1575, 16th century; X.d.428 (136)
      Concerning enclosures in the forest. Until the advent of the Countess of Shrewsbury the ancient customs were maintained. Over 4000 persons affected. Copy, possibly cancelled.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/2ymte7
    - Memoranda of food and drink sent to Buxton for eight days, 1577?; X.d.428 (137)
      Listed day by day from Saturday to Saturday, "befor therle came of Sussex." Probably relates to the Earl of Leicester's visit.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/0d1wbf
    - Inventory of the goods, moveable and unmovable, of the late Francis, Lord Talbot at Thornhill, 1582 September 6; X.d.428 (138)
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/akbhna
    - Note of Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, 1588 October 24; X.d.428 (139)
      A note of the speeches used to the countess of Shrewsbury's tenants at Chatsworth, "by my Lord my fathers Directions."
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/mjb33m
    - Memorandum of George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, for the debt owed to John Keye of Benshawe, Yorkshire and his son, 1589 July 11; X.d.428 (140)
      Also, another memorandum signed by Leonard Bamforth.
      Cancelled with herring-bone incisions; seal removed.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/j0k24i
    - Accounts of costs incurred in litigation, undated; X.d.428 (141)
      Undated from the time of George, Earl of Shrewsbury. Mention of Gilbert Dickenson, a servant.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/4x2b14
    - Petitions from Edward Bramall to Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, 1593?; X.d.428 (142-143)
      Two petitions concerning a dispute about copyhold land in Bradfield, Yorkshire, between two of his tenants, Bramall and Lionel Smylter. The later version, X.d.428 (143), has a memorandum from Gilbert dated September 8, 1593, referring the matter to the custom of his court whose order will be performed by his steward.
      X.d.428 (142) http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/4b8ysd
      X.d.428 (143) http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/reb8zb
    - Petition from Henry Hall to Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, 1597?; X.d.428 (144)
      Concerning a close. A memorandum from Gilbert, dated September 25, 1597, turns the matter over to his bailiff.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/725p93
    - Accounts of Henry Travice, 1597-1598; X.d.428 (145)
      For the periods October 10 to January 17, 1597/8, and overleaf, January 17 to March 11, 1597/8. Annotated and signed by William Cavendish, Earl of Devonshire, April 28, 1598. Refers to Cavendish's leadworks.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/jg2s9x
    - Bill and receipt from John Newland, cutler, to William Cavendish, Earl of Devonshire, 1609/10 February 12; X.d.428 (146)
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/ru3ubc
    - Warrant to collect the customary tithes of Bradfield, 1618/9 February 15; X.d.428 (147)
      Owing on the death of Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury; William Cavendish, Earl of Devonshire was executor to the Earl of Shrewsbury.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/z2q828
- Wentworth family papers, 1627-1705; Series 2; X.d.428 (148-169)
  - Correspondence, 2.1
    - Letter from Humphrey Bagaley, Knowsley, Lancashire, to Sir Thomas Wentworth, bart., Bretton, 1656 October 23; X.d.428 (148)
      Writes on behalf of the Earl of Derby, concerning Lady Derby's business.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/zuelr1
    - Letter from George Barnby, Gunthwaite, Yorkshire to Sir Thomas Wentworth, bart., at "his Lodgings at mistress wentworths a widdow in Swan alley in Colemantreete", 1663/4 March 24; X.d.428 (149)
      Requests that he intercede with Sir George Savile, later Marquis of Halifax, to stop the building of a town mill at Oxspring, Yorkshire by Sir Francis Wortley, bart.
      On the address leaf there is a forwarding address in another hand: "ffor Mistress Mary Wentworth at the Cat fidell in the strand beyond St Clemon's Church," a postal stamp with the date "Mr 25," and the note, "latin for gloues is grotetarum [sic]."
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/n1361m
    - Letter from Peter Burweek, to Grace Montgomery, Countess of Eglinton, Bretton Hall near Wakefield, Yorkshire, 1692 July 21; X.d.428 (150)
      Grace Montgomery, Countess of Eglinton, was the widow of Sir Thomas Wentworth, bart. and married to Alexander, 8th Earl of Eglinton.
      From her physician, advising her on a kidney-related illness. Recommends going to Knaresborough spa, in Yorkshire, and taking Lucatella's balsam.
      Seal almost intact. Note in pencil is in Sir Thomas Phillipps's hand.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/zp086y
    - Letter from Henry de Clifford, Earl of Cumberland, Brougham Castle, Westmorland, to Sir Thomas Wentworth, 1542? March 10; X.d.428 (151)
      Thanks him for entering into a bond on his behalf for the payment of his taxes to the king.
      Sir Thomas Wentworth probably of West Bretton, Yorkshire.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/91uko5
    - Letter from Nathaniel? Johnston to Sir Thomas Wentworth, bart., 1675 April 22; X.d.428 (153)
      From his physician, who has ordered balsam pills and syrup for him. Instructs him that the ale may be sweetened with the syrup of cowslips to taste.
      Nathaniel Johnston name taken from the roll of the Royal College of Physicians, I, 453.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/q20493
    - Letter from Nathaniel? Johnston to Sir Thomas Wentworth, bart., 1675 April 30; X.d.428 (154)
      Instructions from his physician concerning his want of appetite. Includes a receipt for a drink to strengthen his head.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/2r2k2k
    - Letter from Marmaduke Langdale, Baron Langdale, London, to Sir George Wentworth, Woolley, Yorkshire, 1660 July 14; X.d.428 (156)
      Requests Wentworth's opinion as to the appointment of his kinsman Sir Thomas Wentworth, bart. as captain of the trained bands of Barkston Ash and Skircoat, and of Sir Thomas Osborne, later Duke of Leeds, of those of Tickhill and Straffourd. Address leaf includes a note to the postmaster signed by Langdale, the notation "post paid," and "Ferribride" (i.e. Ferrybridge, West Yorkshire)
      Several seals, one intact.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/f0h722
    - Letter from Francis Rockley to Sir George Wentworth, 1658 March 30; X.d.428 (157)
      Concerns Rockley's dispute with Sir John Kay, bart. (the second husband of George's daughter-in-law).
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/3bek12
    - Letter from James Shiers to Sir Thomas Wentworth, bart., Bretton, Yorkshire, 1662/3 February 10; X.d.428 (158)
      Informs him that the decision of the court of King's Bench in the case involving him (Sir Thomas) and his brother, Sir Matthew Wentworth, 2nd bart., went against them. Address leaf includes a note to the postmaster of Ferrybridge and the notation "post paid. 3d."
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/0p24nd
    - Letter from William Wentworth, Earl of Strafford, Rouen, to Sir George Wentworth of Woolley, and Thomas Wentworth, 1648 April 15; X.d.428 (159)
      Concerning payments out of his estate. Presses them to collect his arrears. Would like Thomas Edmunds to become his steward (Edmunds is a known person, d.1663).
      Thomas Wentworth later Sir Thomas Wentworth, bart., of Bretton.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/b6r0t5